[
    {
        "qno": 1,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a valid C data type?",
        "a": "int",
        "b": "float",
        "c": "real",
        "d": "char",
        "correct": "real"
    },
    {
        "qno": 2,
        "question": "C language was developed at which place?",
        "a": "Bell Labs",
        "b": "Microsoft",
        "c": "IBM",
        "d": "Google",
        "correct": "Bell Labs"
    },
    {
        "qno": 3,
        "question": "Which operator is used to get the remainder in C",
        "a": "/",
        "b": "//",
        "c": "%",
        "d": "mod",
        "correct": "%"
    },
    {
        "qno": 4,
        "question": "Which of the following is an entry point of C program?",
        "a": "start()",
        "b": "main()",
        "c": "run()",
        "d": "begin()",
        "correct": "main()"
    },
    {
        "qno": 5,
        "question": "Which format specifier is used to print float values?",
        "a": "%f",
        "b": "%d",
        "c": "%c",
        "d": "%lf",
        "correct": "%f"
    },
    {
        "qno": 6,
        "question": "Which loop executes at least once?",
        "a": "for loop",
        "b": "while loop",
        "c": "do-while loop",
        "d": "switch",
        "correct": "do-while loop"
    },
    {
        "qno": 7,
        "question": "Which function is used to read a single character in C ?",
        "a": "scanf()",
        "b": "getchar()",
        "c": "gets()",
        "d": "input()",
        "correct": "getchar()"
    },
    {
        "qno": 8,
        "question": "Which symbole is used for ssingle line comments in C(C99 standard)?",
        "a": "//",
        "b": "/**/",
        "c": "#",
        "d": "--",
        "correct": "//"
    },
    {
        "qno": 9,
        "question": "What is the default return type of a function in C (if not specified) ?",
        "a": "int",
        "b": "float",
        "c": "void",
        "d": "char",
        "correct": "int"
    },
    {
        "qno": 10,
        "question": "Which header file is used for mathematical function like sqrt(),pow() ?",
        "a": "<math.h>",
        "b": "<stdio.h>",
        "c": "<stdlib.h>",
        "d": "<conio.h>",
        "correct": "<math.h>"
    }
]